

PERSONAL

- Name
 Arden Latraca
- ★ Address Sitio Kasagingan, Banawa, Brgy. Guadalupe, Cebu City 6000 Cebu City
- **Phone number** 09171888863
- Email denzanitized93@gmail.com
- Date of birth 27-10-1993
- Place of birth
 Pasig City
- Website
 http://www.denzanitized.com/
- ⇒ LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/denzi

ARDEN LATRACA

A Senior software developer and Technical lead in my current project. I do have a strong background in Javascript specially in Knockout and Vue as well as JSP in frontend development since the project I am in right now is currently developing the frontend side of the system. However, I still do a bit of backend side such as Java Spring MVC, JSP, JSTL with JBoss as the local server.

I do have 8 years of experience in web development industry since all of my projects are web applications. I have big ambitions in life such as learn a lot of languages as long as I am still in the industry before retirement period. I want to have long term goal and relation with the company that has also has a wide vision for the future.



WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present

SENIOR TECHNICAL DEVELOPER TECH LEAD II

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Lead in the design, development, and implementation of the project
- Perform coding reviews
- Teach the team about the existing project standards and how to implement it during development
- Organize overall development phase

2018 - 2021

SENIOR TECHNICAL DEVELOPER TECH LEAD

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Lead in the design, development, and implementation of the project
- Perform coding reviews
- Teach the team about the existing project standards and how to implement it during development
- Organize overall development phase

2017 - 2018

ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL DEVELOPER II

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Develop applications based from the given client requirements
- Maintain coding standards for readable and maintainable codes
- Ensures the application with quality performance
- Create (HLD and LLD) based from requirements given
- Performs UT and multi-browser testing to maintain application quality
- Deliver the application based from the given client's schedule
- Analyze the best possible way on how to implement things during the development process
- Can work with less supervision
- Technical in terms of development

2016 - 2017

ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL DEVELOPER

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Adapts easily with new environment
- Develop applications given the client's schedule
- Creates unit test cases and perform unit testing when necessary
- Maintains readable codes base on the company coding standards
- Follows internal schedule as much as possible
- Review codes thoroughly
- Learn basics from superiors

2014 - 2016

ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL DEVELOPER

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Develop application for company use
- Design appropriate database design for the system
- Adjust easily with specification changes

- Perform thorough application testing
- Add new features if necessary
- Perform application demo with manager

2012 DATA ENCODER

University of Cebu, Cebu

- Encodes student enrollment form
- Print study load when successfully enrolled
- Drops subject enrolled if requested by student
- Changes subject schedule when requested



EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

2010 - 2014 BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

University of Cebu, Cebu

>>> Consecutive Top Student

>>> Dean's Lister

>>> Graduated with honor - "3rd honor with excellence award"

2006 - 2010 HIGHSCHOOL

University of Cebu, Cebu

>>> Consecutive Top Student

2000 - 2006 **Elementary**

Guadalupe Elementary School, Cebu



SKILLS

Vue JS	****
Knockout JS	****
JQuery	****
JSP	****
CSS/SASS	****
Java Spring	****
HTML	****
Javascript	****
Typescript	****
Webpack	****



ACHIEVEMENTS

>>> JLPT N4 Passer (Issued Jan 2020 · No Expiration Date)

>>> Oracle Java OCA Passer (Issued Jul 2016 · No Expiration Date)